Guide to the Kappa Delta, Sigma Delta Chapter (Duke University) Records, 1935-1981
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Kappa Delta, Sigma Delta Chapter (Duke University) records 1935-1981
University Archives, Duke University
Kappa Delta. Sigma Delta Chapter (Duke University).
1.3 Linear Feet about 1,000 Items
The Sigma Delta Chapter of Kappa Delta was chartered at Duke University in 1912.
Types of material include correspondence, historical accounts, photographs, printed materials, and scrapbooks. Major subjects include student life at Duke University, establishment of a sorority, organization, pledging, initiation, community service activities, social activities, general governance, leadership, and public relations. The collection ranges in date from 1935-1981.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advanced notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Kappa Delta, Sigma Delta Chapter (Duke University) Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1976-1981.
Historical Note
The Sigma Delta Chapter of Kappa Delta was charted at Duke University in 1912. Its charter members included Mary Gorham, Lucille Gorham, Katie Lee McKinnon, Estelle Flowers, and Catherine Thomas.
During 1915, meetings were held in the home of Mary White Cranford. The women wanted a chapter house on campus, but President Few opposed the idea. Sigma Delta continued to have monthly meetings off campus until 1916, when they were granted meeting space in the Woman's Building. In fall 1918, the women moved into a suite in Alspaugh Hall.
During the first year of their Kappa Delta affiliation, the Sigma Delta chapter attended a Halloween party, gave two rushing parties, and attended garden parties. Some other activities enjoyed by the Sigma Delta chapter were: a "Dream Ship Cruise" themed ball with fellow fraternity men, War Chest and YMCA philanthropy, slumber parties, and supporting Hungarian exchange students at Duke. Kappa Delta also participated in Greek Night and created a float for Joe College Weekend.
The Sigma Delta chapter lost its charter in 1967 but was re-chartered in 1976. From 1976 to 1981, the chapter was active on campus, but again lost its charter in 1990. The sorority was formerly governed by the Panhellenic Association at Duke University.
Collection Overview
Types of material include correspondence, historical accounts, photographs, printed materials, and scrapbooks. Major subjects include student life at Duke University, establishment of a sorority, organization, pledging, initiation, community service activities, social activities, general governance, leadership, and public relations. The material ranges in date from 1935-1981.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Kappa Delta. Sigma Delta Chapter (Duke University)
Duke University -- Societies, etc.
Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc.
Greek letter societies -- North Carolina -- Durham
Initiations (into trades, societies, etc.)
Women college students -- North Carolina-- Societies and clubs
Related Material
Photograph Collection
Duke University Archives
Panhellenic Council Records
Duke University Archives
Robert S. Rankin Papers
Duke University Archives
Fraternities and Sororities Collection
Duke University Archives
Margaret Durham Scrapbook
Duke University Archives
Interfraternity Council Records
Duke University Archives
Contents of Collection
- Sigma Delta Chapter Materials, circa 1935-1978
  Contains congratulation letters upon rechartering, a letter to parents about sorority life, photographs, and a typed chapter history.
  - Initiation letter to parents, circa 1935 (Box 1)
  - Letters of Congratulations on installment and reactivation, 1976
  - Chapter History
  - Photographs, 1977-1978
  - Sorority Board Composite Photographs, 1964, 1967 (Opaperfolder 1)
- Printed Material
  Contains bound volumes about the history of Kappa Delta sorority.
  - The History of Kappa Delta Sorority, 1897-1937 (Box 1)
  - A History of Kappa Delta Sorority, 1897-1972
- Scrapbooks, 1957-1981
  Contains scrapbooks from the Sigma Delta Chapter. The 1957-1960 scrapbook was disassembled and placed into folders due to preservation concerns. Materials tucked inside the back cover of the 1975-1977 scrapbook were also placed into folders. Other scrapbooks remain intact and are boxed separately due to their size.
  - 1957-1960, pages 1-30 (Box 1)
  - 1957-1960, pages 31-46
  - 1975-1977, separated materials
  - 50th Anniversary, Sigma Delta Chapter, 1962 (Box 2)
  - 1975-1977
  - Kappa Delta Convention Memory Book, 1977-1981